Neil V. Rosenberg bluegrass music collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Sound recordings, Digital files are located in afc2002009_dc001. Please see the AFC reference staff for access.
  - Osborne Brothers at Antioch College; Plum Creek Boys at Antioch College, AFC 2002/009: SR120
    - Sound recording, Alice Gerrard; RXI 0160; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:46:29, Side 2: 00:47:16): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      - Side 1
        - Osborne Brothers at Antioch College, March 5, 1960
          - "While You're Cheating On Me"
          - invitation to come up to Wheeling some Saturday
          - "Hand Me Down My Walking Cane"
            twin banjos: Benny and Sonny
          - "Jesse James"
          - "He's Knocking"
          - "Foggy Mountain Breakdown"
          - "Jimmy Brown"
          - joke about record sales
          - "Once More"
          - "Molly And Tenbrooks"
          - "White Lightning"
            The intermission may follow this song.
          - "I Wonder How The Old Folks Are At Home"
      - Side 2
        - Osborne Brothers at Antioch College, March 5, 1960
          - "Earl's Breakdown"
          - another record joke
          - "Sweethearts Again"
          - "Little Maggie"
          - "Under Your Spell Again"
          - compliments the audience
          - "Salty Dog Blues"
          - "Pretty Polly"
          - "Send Me The Pillow That You Dream On"
          - "So Low" - Jake, solo
          - "Down In The Willow Garden"
          - "Back Into My Arms Again"
          - "Cripple Creek"
          - spoken interlude
          - "Wildwood Flower"
          - Jenny Foster speaking
          - "Ho, Honey, Ho"
        - Plum Creek Boys at Antioch College, March 5, 1960
          Personnel: Neil Rosenberg, guitar; Charles Crawford, mandolin; John Schuler, banjo; Frank Miller, fiddle.
          - "White House Blues"
          - "Angel Band"
          - "Old Time Religion"
    - Documentation
      - Song list and production notes for SR120, February 7, 2012, pcb1960-03-05.txt; 1 manuscript; black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Old Joe Clarke and the Renfro Valley Gang at Bean Blossom; Baker Brothers at Bean Blossom, August 8, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR121; RXH 8912; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:30:46, Side 2: 00:23:18): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the evening show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Recorded by Neil V. Rosenberg through the house sound system. Personnel: Old Joe Clark, banjo; Shorty Shehan, fiddle; Jim "Tex" Watson, electric bass; Baker Brothers: Jesse, MC and lead vocal, lead guitar; Bob, tenor and rhythm guitar.
    - Side 1
      - Old Joe Clarke and the Renfro Valley Gang
      - Intro - Shorty Shehan
      - Old Joe Clark joking with Shorty
      - "Long John Dean From Bowling Green"
      - Old Joe Clark - comedy routine with Shorty (courting)
      - "Groundhog"
      - Old Joe Clark - comedy routines (crap game as fight, etc.)
      - "Shady Grove (Fly Around My Pretty Little Miss)"
      - Old Joe Clark introduces the Baker Brothers
      - "Just Because" - Baker Brothers
    - Side 2
      - "Soldier And The Lady (The Nightingale)" - Baker Brothers
      - Old Joe Clark asks Shorty to tune the fiddle down; pitch for souvenir booklets
      - "Black Mountain Rag" - Shorty Shehan
      - "Worried Man Blues" - Baker Brothers
      - "March Winds" - Baker Brothers
      - "What Would You Give In Exchange For Your Soul" - Baker Brothers
      - "Lights In The Valley" - Old Joe Clark, Shorty Shehan, Baker Brothers
      - "Chicken Reel" - Shorty Shehan
      - "Fire On The Mountain" - Shorty Shehan
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys; Opry, AFC 2002/009: SR122; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:29:17, Side 2: 00:32:57): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, 1946-1948
        From acetate discs owned by Earl Scruggs. Personnel: Bill Monroe, mandolin and bass lead voice; Lester Flatt, guitar; Earl Scruggs, banjo; Cedric Rainwater (instrument unidentified); Chubby Wise, fiddle,
      - "Molly And Tenbrooks," March 8, 1947
      - "Wicked Path Of Sin," January 3, 1947
      - "Little Maggie," March 23, 1946
      - "Careless Love," March 30, 1946
      - "Shine, Hallelujah, Shine," July 26, 1947
      - "Love Grown Cold," July 26, 1947
      - "Remember The Cross," January 12, 1947
      - "Wicked Path Of Sin," November 23, 1946
        Possibly Wade singing bass rather than Birch.
      - "Little Community Church," December 28, 1946
      - "Blue Yodel No. 4," undated
      - "Will You Be Loving Another Man," April 12, 1947
      - "Wicked Path Of Sin," undated
      - "My Dixie Home," undated
      - "Little Maggie," undated
    - Side 2
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys
      - "As Long As I Live" [fragment] - Bailes Brothers, undated
        This is a more complete version of the same, below.
      - "Just A Little Talk With Jesus," February 21, 1948
      - "Sunny Side Of The Mountain," February 21, 1948
      - "Mother's Only Sleeping," December 21, 1946
      - "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms," December 21, 1946
      - "True Life Blues," April 19, 1947
      - "Why Did You Wander," April 18, 1947
      - "Cumberland Gap," August 2, 1947
        Repeated on the tape; the first time is incomplete.
      - "Blue Yodel No. 4," August 2, 1947
        No bass break, and less yodel at the end.
      - "My Dixie Home," undated
      - "Little Joe," undated
      - "White House Blues," undated
        skips occur
      - "Shining Path," undated
      - "As Long As I Live" - Bailes Brothers, undated
  - Stoney Lonesome Boys at Bean Blossom; Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, AFC 2002/009: SR123; RXH 8913; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:26:11, Side 2: 00:30:55): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Stoney Lonesome Boys at Bean Blossom, September 12, 1965
        Personnel: Roger Smith, fiddle; Osby Smith, mandolin; Vernon McQueen, guitar; Neil V. Rosenberg, banjo; Jim Bessire, bass; Shorty Shehan, MC.
        - "Two Dollar Bill"
          mic falls down
        - "Lonesome Road Blues"
        - "Sweetheart, Can't You Hear Me Calling"
        - "Cabin In Caroline"
        - "Wheel Hoss"
        - "Sweetheart, You Done Me Wrong"
        - "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms"
          Cleata, Rose, and Carol
        - "Bow Down"/"Crying Holy"
        - "I Don't Have The Right"
        - "Fire On The Mountain"
    - Side 2
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, September 12, 1965
        Personnel: Gene Lowinger, fiddle; Pete Rowan, guitar; Neil V. Rosenberg, banjo; Jim Monroe, bass. Continued on SR124.
        - Theme (in C) - "Watermelon"
        - "Panhandle Country"
        - "Dark Hollow"
        - "Walls Of Time"
        - "Shenandoah Valley Breakdown"
        - "Brand New Pair Of Shoes"
        - "Footprints In The Snow"
        - "Muleskinner Blues"
        - "Happy Birthday"
        - "True Life Blues"
        - "Molly And Tenbrooks"
        - "Rawhide"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, September 12, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR124; RXH 8914; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:46, Side 2: 00:31:04): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Personnel: Gene Lowinger, fiddle; Pete Rowan, guitar; Neil V. Rosenberg, banjo; Jim Monroe, bass. Continued from SR123; continued on SR125.
    - Side 1
      - Afternoon show, Recorded at the Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana.
        - "Cry, Cry, Darling"
        - "Stone's Rag" - Birch Monroe
        - "Cairo" - Birch Monroe
        - "Bllechh" [sic]... - Mr. George Rutherford
        - "A Beautiful Life"
        - "Somebody Touched Me"
        - "I Saw The Light"
        - "Wayfaring Stranger"
        - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
        - "Uncle Pen"
        - "Shake My Mother's Hand For Me'
        - "Orange Blossom Special"
    - Side 2
      - Afternoon show
        - "Little Girl And The Dreadful Snake"
        - "Highway Of Sorrow"
        - "Out Of The Cold World"
        - "Cheyenne"
        - "White House Blues"
        - "Kentucky Waltz"
        - "Hills Of Roane County"
        - "Y'all Come"
      - Gene and Roger, in the back room
        - "Old Joe Clark"
      - Evening show
        Same band
        - "Brown County Breakdown"
        - "I Ain't Broke But I'm Badly Bent"
        - "Live And Let Live"
        - "Salt Creek"
        - "Rawhide"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, September 12, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR125; RXH 8915; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:05, Side 2: 00:10:34): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the evening show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Personnel: Gene Lowinger, fiddle; Pete Rowan, guitar; Neil V. Rosenberg, banjo; Jim Monroe, bass. Continued from SR124.
    - Side 1
      - "Muleskinner Blues"
      - "Footprints In The Snow"
      - "In The Pines"
      - "Panhandle Country"
      - "Cry, Cry, Darling"
      - "Monroe's Hornpipe"
      - "Sally Goodin"
      - "Old Joe Clark"
      - "Natural Bridge Blues"
      - "Boating Up Sandy"
      - "Just A Little Talk With Jesus"
      - "Boat Of Love"
      - "Shenandoah Valley Breakdown"
    - Side 2
      - "Kentucky Waltz"
      - "Stoney Lonesome"
      - "Uncle Pen"
      - "On And On"
      - "Y'all Come"
  - Osborne Brothers at Bean Blossom, September 26, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR126; RXH 8916; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:28, Side 2: 00:30:28): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Continued on SR127.
    - Side 1
      - Afternoon show
        - "Cumberland Gap"
        - "I Know What It Means To Be Lonesome"
        - "The Banjo Boys"
        - "This Heart Of Mine"
        - "Fair And Tender Ladies"
        - "Greensleeves"
        - "Take This Hammer"
        - "The Cuckoo"
        - "Foggy Mountain Breakdown"
        - "Lonesome Road Blues"
        - "Charlie Cotton"
        - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
        - "Molly And Tenbrooks"
    - Side 2
      - Afternoon show
        - "Steal Away"
        - "Little Maggie"
        - "I'll Be Alright Tomorrow"
        - "Hey, Hey Bartender"
        - "Ruby"
      - Evening show
        - "Cumberland Gap"
        - "Me And My Old Banjo"
        - "Making Plans"
        - "Greensleeves"
  - Osborne Brothers at Bean Blossom, September 26, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR127; RXH 8917; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:30:26, Side 2: 00:36:47): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the evening show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Continued from SR126. There is a note in the documentation that an interview Neil Rosenberg conducted with Bob Osborne follows the songs (on the same date and in the same place, in the back room after the show), but the interview is not to be copied. It begins on Side 2, about 00:17:46.
    - Side 1
      - "Ruby"
      - "Sweethearts Again"
      - "Sally Goodin"
      - "Charlie Cotton"
      - "I Know What It Means To Be Lonesome"
      - "Give This Message To Me Heart"
      - "Green, Green Grass Of Home"
      - "Sunny Mountain Chimes"
      - "Billy In The Low Ground"
      - "Once More"
    - Side 2
      - "Bugle Call Rag"
      - "Pathway Of Teardrops"
      - "Each Season Changes You"
      - "Footprints In The Snow"
      - "Salty Dog Blues"
      - "John Henry"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, October 3, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR128; RXH 8918; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:35, Side 2: 00:28:13): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the afternoon show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Personnel: Pete Rowan, guitar; Gene Lowinger, fiddle; Lamar Grier, banjo. Continued on SR129.
    - Side 1
      - "Brown County Breakdown"
      - "Stoney Lonesome"
      - "I'm Not Broke, Just Badly Bent"
      - "True Life Blues"
      - "Salt Creek"
      - "Big Sandy River"
      - "On And On"
      - "Monroe's Hornpipe"
      - "Roane County Prison"
      - "Footprints In The Snow"
      - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
        A string breaks on Rowan's guitar; an intermission is called.
    - Side 2
      - "Soldier's Joy"
      - "Carroll County Blues"
        Birch on the fiddle
      - "Oscar Stone Rag"
      - "The Boat Of Love"
        Birch sings bass
      - "A Beautiful Life"
      - "Life's Railway to Heaven"
      - "Raw Hide"
      - "Linda Lou"
      - "Panhandle Country"
      - "Y'all Come"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, October 3, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR129; RXH 8919; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:33:01, Side 2: 00:29:11): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the evening show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Personnel: Pete Rowan, guitar; Gene Lowinger, fiddle; Lamar Grier, banjo; Jim Monroe, bass. Continued from SR128.
    - Side 1
      - Theme
      - "Big Mon"
      - "Walls Of Time"
      - "Dark Hollow"
      - "Pine County Breakdown"
      - "Muleskinner Blues"
      - "I'm Going Back To Old Kentucky"
      - "Footprints In The Snow"
      - "Watson Blues"
      - "Kentucky Mandolin"
      - "Wayfaring Stranger"
    - Side 2
      - "Wayfaring Stranger"
        End of the song
      - "Uncle Pen"
        An intermission follows the song.
      - "Stoney Point"
      - "Florida Blues"
      - "I'll Fly Away"
      - "Precious Memories"
      - "Have A Little Talk With Jesus"
      - "The Old, Old House"
      - "I Live In The Past"
      - "Shady Grove"
      - "Y'all Come"
  - Wakefield and Allen, WDON, summer 1963, AFC 2002/009: SR130; Scott Hambly; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:31:10, Side 2: 00:32:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Also known as The Kentuckians. Personnel: Red Allen, Frank Wakefield, Pete Kuykendall, Tom Morgan. Broadcast on WDON, Arlington or Falls Church, Virginia. See SR131.
    - Side 1
      - "Cryin' Heart Blues"
      - "Give Me Flowers While I'm Living"
      - "Blue and Lonesome"
      - "Beaumont Rag" [?]
      - "(Someday, Sweetheart) When You Are Lonely"
      - "Salty Dog Blues"
      - "Somebody Loves You, Darling"
      - "Darling Pal Of Mine"
      - "Are You Afraid To Die"
      - "Rose Lee McFall"
      - "My Baby's Gone"
      - "Back Up And Push"
      - "100 Years From Now"
      - "Pain In My Heart"
      - "Bluegrass Stomp"
    - Side 2
      - "I Wonder If You Feel The Way I Do"
      - "Will You Be Satisfied That Way"
      - "Ashes Of Love"
      - "Deep Ellem [Ellum] Blues"
      - "Sunny South"
      - "You'll Always Be My Blue-Eyed Darling"
      - "Pike County Breakdown"
      - "Little Girl And The Dreadful Snake"
      - "Paul And Silas"
      - "Little Rosewood Casket"
      - "I Thought I'd Never Fall In Love Again"
      - "Goodbye Booze"
      - "Chocolate Ice Cream Cone"
      - "Today Has Been A Lonesome Day"
      - "Summertime Is Past And Gone"
  - Wakefield and Allen, WDON; Wakefield and Allen at Gerdes' Folk City, New York City, AFC 2002/009: SR131; Scott Hambly; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:30:03, Side 2: 00:32:25): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Wakefield and Allen, WDON, summer 1963
        See SR130.
        - "I'll Go On Dreaming Just The Same"
        - "Pistol Packing Momma"
        - "Here Today And Gone Tomorrow"
        - "Back Up And Push"
        - "Long Journey Home"
        - "Poison Love"
        - "New Camptown Races"
        - "This Land Is Your Land"
        - "Old Joe Clark"
        - "Calling My Name"
        - "Going Over Jordan"
        - "Poor Ellen Smith"
        - "Don't Laugh"
        - "I Don't Love Nobody"
    - Side 2
      - Wakefield and Allen, WDON, summer 1963
        - "Salt Creek"
        - "Sing, Sing, Sing"
        - "I Wonder Why You Said Goodbye"
        - "I Wouldn't Change You If I Could"
      - Wakefield and Allen at Gerdes' Folk City, New York City, fall 1963
        - "On My Way Back To The Old Home"
        - "Will You Be Loving Another Man"
        - "Nobody's Darling But Mine"
        - "Bass Boogie" (comic intro)
        - "Somebody Loves You, Darling"
        - "Sunny South"
        - "Nobody Loves Me, Nobody Cares"
        - "God Gave You To Me"
        - "Little Birdie" [incomplete]
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, November 7, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR132; RXH 8920; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:30, Side 2: 00:32:40): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the afternoon show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Personnel: Pete Rowan, guitar; Lamar Grier, banjo; Gene Lowinger, fiddle; James Monroe, bass. Continued on SR133.
    - Side 1
      - Theme
      - "Brown County Breakdown"
      - "Today Has Been A Lonesome Day"
      - "Live And Let Live"
      - "Lonesome Road Blues"
      - "Billy In The Low Ground"
      - "Uncle Pen"
      - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
      - "Footprints In The Snow"
      - "Little Joe"
      - "Going To The Races"
      - "Two Little Boys"
    - Side 2
      - "Two Little Boys"
      - "I Live In The Past"
      - "Salt Creek"
      - "Molly And Tenbrooks"
      - "Panhandle Country"
      - "Little Girl And The Dreadful Snake"
      - "Bluegrass Breakdown"
      - "Highway Of Sorrow"
      - "Down Yonder"
      - "Over The Waves"
      - "Carroll County Blues"
      - "A Beautiful Life"
      - "Life's Railway to Heaven"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, November 7, 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR133; RXI 0187; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:26, Side 2: 00:32:39): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the afternoon show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Personnel: Pete Rowan, guitar; Lamar Grier, banjo; Gene Lowinger, fiddle; James Monroe, bass. Continued from SR132; continued on SR134.
    - Side 1
      - Afternoon show
        - "Christmas Time's A'Coming"
        - "Tall Timber"
        - "Jimmy Brown"
        - "Y'all Come"
      - Evening show
        - "Stoney Lonesome"
        - "Walls Of Time"
        - "Dark Hollow"
        - "Wildwood Flower"
        - "Girl In The Blue Velvet Band"
        - Medley
          - "Pretty Polly"
          - "Little Georgia Rose"
          - "Brand New Shoes"
          - "Molly And Tenbrooks"
          - "Little Maggie"
          - "Pretty Polly"
    - Side 2
      - Evening show
        - "Raw Hide"
        - "Muleskinner"
        - "Kentucky Mandolin"
        - "Lost Train Blues"
        - "Florida Blues"
        - "Chicken Reel"
          Birch and Bill
        - "Just A Little Talk With Jesus"
        - "I Saw The Light"
        - "Shenandoah Breakdown"
        - "Put My Little Shoes Away"
        - "I Cried Again"
        - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
        - "Wayfaring Stranger"
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom; Grand Ole Opry, AFC 2002/009: SR134; RXI 0188; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:10:20, Side 2: 00:31:21): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Continued from SR133.
    - Side 1
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom, November 7, 1965
        Recorded at the evening show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Pete Rowan, guitar; Lamar Grier, banjo; Gene Lowinger, fiddle; Jim Monroe, bass.
        - "Wayfaring Stranger"
        - "Uncle Pen"
          With a "true story" introduction.
        - "Y'all Come"
      - Grand Ole Opry, radio station WSM, Nashville, Tennessee, January 8, 1966
        - Martha White theme - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Gonna Have Myself A Ball" - Flatt and Scruggs
          With harp
        - "Eighth Of January" - Crook Brothers
        - "Houston" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "Fallen Leaves" - Grandpa Jones
        - "Foggy Mountain Breakdown" - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "I Live In The Past" - Bill Monroe
        - "Johnny B. Goode" - Jim and Jesse
        - "Memories" - Osborne Brothers
        - "Detroit City" - Flatt and Scruggs
    - Side 2
      - Grand Ole Opry, radio station WSM, Nashville, Tennessee, January 8, 1966
        - "Houston" [again] - Flatt and Scruggs
        - "The Old, Old House" - Bill Monroe
        - "Milk 'Em In The Evening Blues" - Sam and Kirk McGee
        - "Memphis" - Jim and Jesse
  - Bobby Thompson, Bill Keith, and Steve Arkin; "The Crepitation Contest"; Paul Cadwell; Allen Shelton, AFC 2002/009: SR135; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:26:38, Side 2: 00:26:54): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    See SR152 for a more complete version of the Bobby Thompson and Bill Keith recording.
    - Side 1
      - Bobby Thompson, Bill Keith, and Steve Arkin, July 1964
        Bobby Thompson, banjo. Recorded in Converse, South Carolina, by Bill Keith (second banjo) and Steve Arkin (guitar).
        - "Shucking The Corn"
          Brief fragment
        - "Stoney Creek"
        - "Bill Cheatham"
          The second part is the same as on the 1958 tape.
        - "Swanee"/"Humoresque"
        - "Arkansas Traveler"
        - "Old Joe Clark"
          twin banjos
        - "Nola"
        - "Fisher's Hornpipe"
        - "Little Rock Getaway"
        - "The Birth Of The Blues"
          Trischka has this as "Ain't Misbehaving"
        - "Dixie Hoedown"
          Twin banjos
        - "Groundspeed"
        - "Fallington" [?]
          Jazzy piece
        - talk
        - "Crazy Fingers"
          hornpipe
        - "Sugarfoot Rag"
        - "Flop-Eared Mule"
        - Fragment of "Salty Dog" or another circle of fifths piece. Trischka calls this a ragtime tune.
        - "Caravan"
          Played twice; the second time with guitar
        - "I Wish I Could Fall In Love Today"
          Jim McReynolds tune; Trischka notes this as "steel guitarish tune"
        - "Arkansas Traveler"
          Classical style
        - "Dixie"/"Yankee Doodle"
          Thompson on guitar
        - "Winter Walking"
          Another guitar piece played by Thompson; an unnamed Merle Travis tune. Trischka notes this as "blues (circle of fourths)"
        - "Cripple Creek"
    - Side 2
      - Bobby Thompson, Bill Keith, and Steve Arkin, July 1964
        - "Cripple Creek"
          One of Jimmy Buchanan's tunes
        - "Tico Tico"
        - "Lullaby Of Birdland"
          Trischka calls this fragment "jazz standard"
        - "I Could Have Danced All Night"
        - "Unfinished Symphony"
          Fiddle tune
        - "Casey Jones"
        - "Liza Jane"
      - "The Crepitation Contest," circa 1946
        Dubs of a set of four 45 rpm discs
      - "Leisure Moments" - Paul Cadwell
      - unidentified classical banjo work - Paul Cadwell
      - "Wildwood Flower" - Allen Shelton
  - Brownie McGhee; Dallas Henderson; "White House Blues"; Pretty Polly variants; The Country Gentlemen at Oberlin; "Zolgotz", AFC 2002/009: SR136; RXI 0161; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:11:55, Side 2: 00:17:40): analog, 7 1/2 ips and 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Vendor's digitization note: Special treatment was performed on Side 1 to splice segments at different speeds into one file at the correct speed. There was heavy distortion on the latter half of Side 1 and across Side 2, with speed fluctuations and wow on both sides, brief dropouts/gaps of silence, and static across both sides. There was high frequency loss on the latter half of Side 2.
    - Side 1
      - Brownie McGhee at Oberlin, circa 1959
        Recorded at Oberlin College
        - "Me and Old Sonny"
        - "Death of Big Bill"
        - "Take My Hand, Precious Lord"
          The recording was cut off about mid-way through the performance.
      - Dallas Henderson, December 27, 1962
        Vocal accompanied by banjo. Recorded in Indianapolis, Indiana, by Pat Dunford and Art Rosenbaum.
        - "Pretty Polly"
        - "Lost Indian"